## **CURRICULUM VITAE**

### **HENG Vongkol**

Borey Sorla #30-B, St. 371, Toeuk Thla, Posenchey, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia (855) 86 397 627 hengvongkol@gmail.com

### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Gender : Male

Date of Birth : February 10, 1987

Material Status: Single

Place of Birth : Kampot Province, Kingdom of Cambodia

Nationality : Khmer

### **WORKING EXPERIENCES**

### **SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATION**

I have been serving as a web and database developer for several years in both company and non-profit organization. I involved in many database and website projects including managing, leading, maintaining, developing and testing the project as well. I have also been serving as a web development trainer for several years and has developed many students in web programming. I experienced a lot in problem solving in term of computer programming and team work.

### **SKILLS AND PERSONAL PERFORMANCES:**

- Outstanding Communication Skills
- Advisory and training skill
- Software project management (planning, development, monitoring, risk, resource, budget, scrum master)
- Time Management and problem solving
- Fast learning, flexible and multi-tasking
- Organizing and Resource Management Skills
- Professional Attitude
- Team Work and independent work
- Managerial and Computer Skills
- Report Writing & Record Keeping Skills
- Able to Follow Instructions, provide feedback and suggestion
- Result Oriented

### July 2016 – Present Implementing and customizing eLearning Platform Personal Project

The main goal of this project is to provide free IT training to everyone with full online classroom experience in Khmer through their devices including PC, tablet, and smartphone.

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Studying and analyzing existing workflow of the platform
- Identifying the missing components or feature to be added or modified
- Controlling code repository
- Adding Khmer language to the platform
- Implementing and deploying system to the server
- Customizing and developing the platform
- Monitoring and maintenance the system
- Creating pilot courses
- Marketing the platform

### 2015 – Present

Head of Developer and Senior Developer PMH Asia Family Co., Ltd, Kingdom of Cambodia

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Manage developer team for project development
- Coordinate developer team for good process of development
- Build developer team spirit and solve problems
- Manage and assign task to developer
- Study and analyze solution for business operation and transforming into application
- Analyze project specifications and developed software specifications for the project
- Manage, develop and maintain website of the company
- Design ads banner and leaflet of the company
- Manage social network account of the company
- Write product documentation and do training
- Develop business and e-commerce websites for client
- Lead developer team to develop database program

#### 2013 - 2015

#### **Web Development Trainer**

### Passerelles numériques Cambodia (PNC), Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Take part in curriculum development and improvement
- Create and update various course outlines
- Create and update course content for various subject such as Database Development, C
  Programming, PHP Programming, HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, C#, ASP.NET, PHP MVC
  Framework, Responsive Design, Project Management and more
- Train, monitor and assess students
- Join developer team to develop school website
- Join developer team to develop School Management System (SMS) for managing students
- Join selection team to select student from province
- Role as an advisor and counselor for interned students
- Initiating and developing eLearning platform

### 2012 - 2015

### Freelance Web Designer and Database Developer

### **Key Experiences:**

- Having experience on dealing with different clients in different situations
- Leading and developing project with a very tied deadline and with no supervision
- Creating project key specs, agreement and quotation with clients
- Designing web template and banner website
- Analyzing and developing business application such as Project Management System, Remote Power Control System, Accounting System, HR Management System
- Joining the government to develop some applications including Mission Control, Schedule Management, Chatting System and Civil Servant Management System
- Outsourcing for developing ecommerce website and reporting system
- Updating and maintenance website and system
- Client training and system deployment
- Writing website content and graphic tweaking

### 2011 - 2013

### **Database Developer**

### MSJ Asia Technology Co., Ltd, Kingdom of Cambodia

- Performed all assigned duties from project manager
- Analyze and develop database specs for the required application
- Discuss and propose solutions for the problem in the project
- Create project documentation and developer specification
- Collect requirements from customer
- Design UX for application
- Develop backend database code for the required application

- Write logic code for the project
- Report task to manager
- Propagate tasks and solutions in development team

### 2011 - 2012

### Web Design Instructor (Part Time)

### Information Technology and Electronic Center, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

- Training student in various subjects such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Adobe Flash, Photoshop, Dreamweaver
- Design course outline in an alignment with student level and need
- Create course content and sample work students
- Feedback and assess student
- Report to school principle

### 2009 - 2010

# Computer Instructor / Head of Computer Instructor IPAT Institute, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia Key Responsibilities:

- Leading computer instructor team to develop course content for training
- Training student various subject including MS Word, Excel, Powerpoint, MS Access, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Flash, computer repair and maintenance
- Observe and follow up student to make sure they are progressing
- Evaluate and test student for upgrading level
- Repair and maintenance computers in the lab
- Report to school principle
- Create database system in MS Access for managing students
- Design and implement network infrastructure for internal use
- Maintenance and sharing printers
- Participate in developer team to design and develop school website

### 2008 - 2009

#### **Construction Worker**

### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Implement all tasks assigned by site manager
- Laying bricks
- Tie steel for column and beam
- Mix concrete

### **ACADEMIC EDUCATION**

#### 2007 - 2011

Bachelor in Computer Science & Engineering, Cambodian Mekong University, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

#### 2007 - 2009

Diploma in Civil Construction, Preah Kossomak Polytechnic Institute, Phnom Penh, kingdom of Cambodia

### 2004 - 2007

Graduated High School, Hun Sen Chamkadong, Kep, Kingdom of Cambodia

### **Technologies and Programming Languages**

C, C++, C#, VB, VBA, Java, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Ajax, JSON, XML, Bootstrap, Angular, PHP, Codelgniter, MVC, Laravel, ASP.NET, Web API, Windows Forms, SQL, MySQL, MS SQL Server, OOP, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Online, Eclipse, TCP/IP, HTTP, HTTPS, GitHubs, NetBeans, IIS, Apache Web Server, Hosting, Cpanel, MS Office, MS Access, Cordova, Hybrid Mobile App, Ionic, Android, Scrum framework, SDLC, responsive design, Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal, Opencart, Claroline, Chamilo, PHPMaker, Adobe Flash, SEO, Google Map, PC maintenance and more in the learning list

### TRAINING COURSES AND WORKSHOP

### **Sep 2013**

Certificated of Advanced Training Techniques for Professional Trainers from ACE, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

#### **Apr 2013**

Completed training course on Java Server Page Development from PN Cambodia, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

### June 2014

Completed training course on Software Project Management from PN Cambodia, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

### Oct 2014

Completed training course on Pedagogy from PN Cambodia, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

### May 2015

Completed training course on Search Engine Optimization from PN Cambodia, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

#### Oct 2010 - Dec 2010

Completed the course of TESOL from IPAT Institute, Phnom Penh, Kingdom of Cambodia

### **LANGUAGES**

Language	<u>Reading</u>	<u>Writing</u>	<u>Listening</u>	<u>Speaking</u>
Khmer (Mother Tongue)	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent
English	Good	Good	Good	Good

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

### Human Resource Management System Project 5 months As System Developer

- Designed Data Flow with documentation for project modules
- Design database and write stored programming on database server
- Design graphical user interface for the application
- Coding and testing different project module
- Testing application
- Collecting requirement
- Report to project manager

### **E-Commerce Website**

### **Project 3 months**

### As Web Developer

- Developed web application project with PHP, PHP Framework (CI), MySQL, and include with JSON, JavaScript / jQuery, AJAX, Bootstrap, and etc.
- Developed chat module to integrate with ecommerce website
- Developed SMS module to send message to customer mobile phone
- Developed QR code module for product online

### **Gasoline Management System**

### **Project 5 months**

### As Project Manager and Developer

- Designed Data Flow with documentation for Developers; prepared repository to manage sources control and assigned tasks to developer
- Managed and Implemented software project, primarily in C#, ASP.NET MVC 5, Microsoft SQL Server. Worked with other programmers to implement new features and fix bugs as needed
- Work closely with Developers to try and break and find bugs in software; consider all possible scenarios
- Log problems into bug tracking software and assist in making sure all bugs and new features are implemented for each scheduled release
- Developed some module of the program such as Card control, Inventory and Customer Management

# **Civil Servant Management System Project 3 months**

### As Web Developer

- Designed web application template and form assigned by project leader
- Joined team to analyze requirements and writing application specs
- Developed database structure and create stored programming
- Tested and reported bugs and requested feature to team leader
- Joined developer team to code on different modules of the program

### **Accounting Management System**

### **Project 4 months**

### As Project Manager and Web Developer

- Lead developer team to design and develop application
- Writing application and database specs for developer
- Analyze and create program flow
- Create application user interface and form
- Joined developer team to code on different modules of the program such as Item List, Customer Center, Vendor Center, Chart of Account and more

### Website for NGO and Company

### More than 7 projects

### As Project Leader and Web Developer

- Handling the project life cycle
- Responsible for the whole creation of the website including
  - o Template design
  - o Email login integration
  - Database design
  - Coding
  - Testing
  - Hosting
- Design photo for the website
- Dealing with customer for requirement
- Maintenance and update website

### **HOBBIES AND INTEREST**

- Web research on new IT technology
- Sport (Football and volleyball)
- Create video training

### **REFFERENCES**

### Mr. PEN Oudom

**Head of MIS,** Delta Microfinance Plc E-mail : oudom.pen@gmail.com

Mobile: (855) 96 401 6264

### Mr. HOUR Bunthoeurn

**Head of IT,** Try Pheap Group E-mail : hbthoeurn@gmail.com

Mobile: (855) 10 517 388